Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
-==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：景鲤
翻译：景鲤 欣欣然 Mabb 苑琳琳
校对：veray Uriana
Once upon a time...
很久以前...
not so long ago...
其实也不算太久...
奇异恐惧
东伦敦 哈克尼区
Ah!
啊!
This is the story of me.
这就是我的故事
Jack.
我叫杰克
There I am, absolutely shitting it.
我就是这么一个爱死了逃避的人
I'd been carrying a carving knife with me for three weeks
由于内心有一种害怕被谋杀的荒谬恐惧
due to an irrational fear of being murdered.
这三个礼拜以来我都随身带着雕刻刀
I couldn't sleep at night.
而且夜不能寐
As soon as I got into bed, I started seeing killers.
我一上床 就看见杀手来了
These killers were the subject of a series of plays
这些杀手是我曾经为电视台写的一部剧
I had been writing for television.
里面的主题人物
The nature of the project necessitated research
这个节目的本质就是研究
into heinous Victorian criminals.
维多利亚女王时期那些穷凶极恶的犯人
And I had unwittingly familiarized myself with all the famous hackers,
我不知不觉就熟悉了19世纪所有著名的
dosers and severers of the 19th century.
黑客 病毒和凶徒
Faces that would've frightened the Ripper.
他们令开膛手杰克都胆战心惊
Many a long night I spent there,
我在这度过了许多个漫漫长夜
drenched in thoughts of bloody murder.
满脑子都是血腥的谋杀
I became particularly disturbed by a man I called The Hendon Ogre.
那个被我称作亨顿食人魔的男人尤其让我惴惴不安
A maniac from North London who had boiled the arsenic out of fly papers
这个自伦敦北部的疯子 用灭蝇纸熬成了砒霜
and introduced the result into his lodger's broth.
倒进了他房客的肉汤里
I'd lie awake for hours, thinking of the brute,
我久久不能入睡 想着这个畜生
terrified someone was slipping arsenic into my diet.
害怕有人也会把砒霜倒进我的饭里
In the mornings, I'd inspect grapefruit and milk bottle tops
早上起来 我会仔细检查我的葡萄柚和牛奶瓶盖
looking for evidence of interference with syringes.
寻找注射器插过的痕迹
Trivial events became vital clues in the detection of my assassin.
琐碎的事情在我对暗杀的侦查之下都变成了重要的线索
If the telephone rang at half past four, I'd look at the clock and say,
如果4点半的时候电话响了 我会看看钟 说到
"it was half past four when the telephone rang that fateful evening.
"在那个关键的夜晚 电话在4点半的时候响起
How could anyone have known at the time
怎么会有人知道此刻
how important that telephone call was to become?"
这个电话会成为多么重要的线索?"
My situation became unbearable.
我的情况实在是忍无可忍了
I suspected everyone and everything.
我怀疑所有的人事物
Innocent passersby.
包括无辜的路人
Creeks in the corridor.
走廊上的克里克人(美国印第安部落)
Bumps in the night got so bad, I started plugging my head shut.
在夜里 大脑思绪太过活跃 我不得不堵住它
But I'd soon have to get up and check for killers in the bathroom,
不过 用不了多久 我就得起床来检查浴室里有没有杀手
in the kitchen...
还要看看厨房里...
in the fridge,
冰箱里
or in the hallway,
还有走廊上
where they kept a low profile,
他们会低调行事
crawling about in the shadows, lurking behind creaky doors.
潜伏在吱吱作响的门后面 躲在暗处伺机而动
Ah!
啊!
Bloody windows, bloody draughts.
该死的窗户 该死的空气
Oh, God, come on.
噢 天哪 别这样了
Argh!
啊!
This fear that I would be murdered all began sometime before.
这种担心被谋杀的感觉始于不久之前
At lunch, to be exact.
确切的说 是在某个午饭时间
The day I saw my literary agent...
我去见我的文稿代理人的那天...
- Newspaper?  - Clair De Grunwald.
- 报纸要吗?  - 她就是克莱尔·古伦王德
- Thanks.  - No problem.
- 谢了  - 不客气
She'd arranged to meet me at a respectable establishment in SoHo.
她安排我们在索豪区的一家高档餐厅见面
You like newspaper?
要读报吗?
- Shall I bring sir the wine list?  - Yes. Okay.
- 需要我为您把酒单拿来吗?  - 嗯 好的
Pleasure.
不客气
"The body was found in the East End of London,
"在东伦敦找到一具尸体
but the Hanoi Handshake is the unmistakable calling card
但是河内握手信号表明这显然是
of a Vietnamese gang killing.
一群越南人造成的杀戮
According to one unnamed police source
一位不愿意透露姓名的警方人员表示
downtown Hackney, also known as Little Vietnam
有着小越南之称的哈克尼区
is now a bloody jungle...
现在完全是一个有组织犯罪的...
of organized crime.
血腥丛林
The missing fingers have yet to be found."
失踪的手指目前还没有找到"
Newspaper?
要报纸吗?
- Whoa, hey, no...  - Sir.
- 哇 嘿 别...  - 先生
- No, it... Please...  - Jack?
- 别动... 拜托了...  - 杰克 你怎么了?
- Clair.  - Under the table already?
- 嘿 克莱尔  - 看来你已经醉了?
It's not even 12:00.
还不到12点呢
- No, I...  - I'm sorry.
- 不 我只是...  - 抱歉
I'm afraid I only have an hour.
恐怕我只能给你一个小时
I've got to go meet Ragsie Lawrence.
我还要去见瑞格丝·劳伦斯
Remember Ragsie? The dancing dyke?
还记得瑞格丝·劳伦斯吗? 就是那个跳舞的同性恋
She's just been made commissioning editor at the BBC.
她刚刚成为英国广播电台的责任编辑
Can you believe it?
你信吗?
Never underestimate a hunchback, that's what I say.
所以说 永远不要低估任何人
- Are you staying there all lunch?  - No, sorry.
- 你要那么坐着吃午饭吗?  - 不 抱歉
Anyway...
不管这么说...
It's good timing. I can tell her how busy you are with your murders.
时机不错 我可以告诉她你正忙着编纂你的谋杀案呢
- Up to my elbows.  - Good.
- 忙得不可开交啊  - 很好
- Do you have a title?  - "Decades of Death".
- 想好题目了吗?  - "死亡年代"
- Chilling.  - Well, if you want murder...
- 够酷  - 其实 如果想写谋杀案...
then Victorian Britain is the golden age.
英国维多利亚女王时代绝对是黄金时期
I think murder's lost its sense of theatre. What do we have now?
我觉得谋杀已经失去了剧场的感觉 我们现在有什么?
- It's just like kids...  - Mindless violence?
- 就像孩子那么幼稚...  - 愚蠢的暴力?
Exactly. Yes. Killers don't put any thought into their murders anymore.
对 就是愚蠢的暴力 杀手都不再好好谋划他们的罪行了
- Have you heard of Long Ear?  - Can't say I have, no.
- 你听说过长耳朵的故事吗?  - 这我可真不知道
Terrifying Polish plumber who hacked off a Frenchman's head.
一个可怕地波兰水管工 他砍掉了一个法国人的脑袋
Disposed of the limbs, but couldn't think of what to do with the head.
肢解了四肢 却不知道如何处理这个头颅
Eventually he utilized his gas-fired crucible,
最后他利用燃气的坩埚
filled the mouth with lead, slung the thing in the river.
把他嘴里塞满了铅 把头颅扔到了河里
Can you imagine?
你能想象出来吗?
I'm sorry, sir. This is a non-smoking restaurant. Thank you.
抱歉 先生 我们这里禁烟 谢谢合作
- Are you ready to order, madam?  - Do you know what you're having?
- 女士 您准备点餐了吗?  - 想好要吃什么了吗?
I'll just have a beer. I'm not very hungry.
喝酒就行了 我还不太饿
- One beer.  - This is my treat, darling.
- 一瓶啤酒  - 这顿我来请 亲爱的
Well, then I will have the chicory salad with asparagus croutons,
这样的话 那再给我来一份苦苣沙拉 开胃菜还要芦笋面包丁
chorizo and poached egg to start.
西班牙辣香肠和荷包蛋
Followed by the salmon and leek fish cake
然后上一份鲑鱼韭菜蛋糕
with mushy peas, chips and chive cream. Thank you. Lovely.
再有豌豆糊 薯条和细香葱 多谢了 亲爱的
People love a good murder.
人们总是喜欢精彩的谋杀案
I began to tell Clair about my good friend Professor Friedkin,
我开始跟克莱尔讲我的朋友弗莱德金教授的事
author of an influential paper on the criminalstare,
曾写过一篇影响深远 讨论犯罪视角的论文
an ocular condition that instantly identified a madman.
他有立刻辨认出疯子的锐利眼光
Monsieur?
先生?
Jack?
嘿 杰克?
Jack? Jack?
杰克? 杰克 你怎么了?
Jack?
嘿 杰克?
- Jack?  - Yes. Sorry.
- 喂 没事吧?  - 没事 抱歉
- Are you all right?  - Yes.
- 你没事吧?  - 嗯
Yes. I'm sorry.
我没事 对不起
- What was I talking about?  - The book.
- 我刚刚讲到哪了?  - 书
- The criminal stare.  - Oh, yes, yes. the criminal stare.
- 犯罪视角  - 嗯 对 就是犯罪视角
Yeah. I found... I've trawled through hundreds of these photographs and...
我发现了... 我网罗了数百张照片...
Um, when you kill someone, when you take a life,
如果你杀了人 犯了杀戒
you acquire these awful eyes, you know, like a shark or a chicken.
你就会有可怕的眼神 想想 就像鲨鱼或者鸡那样的眼神
- How frightful.  - But it's not just a horror show.
- 真可怕  - 那不仅仅是场恐怖表演
I've realised that's not the reason I have to write this.
我意识到这不是我写下这些的原因
No, it's a detective story, you see, about how they become killers.
这是个侦探故事 讲述他们如何成为杀手的
How do they get there? What fills them with need to victimize and kill?
他们如何到那里去的? 是什么驱使他们进行杀戮和破坏?
- Why choose mass murder?  - Why not become a writer?
- 为什么选择大规模屠杀?  - 为什么不当个作家呢?
Well, actually, writers and serial killers are very similar.
其实 作家和连环杀手是很相似的
They're practically brothers.
他们实际上就是兄弟
Hemingway says, “What do you need to become a writer?
海明威说过"成为一名作家需要些什么?
An unhappy childhood." It's the same thing with serial killers.
一个悲惨的童年" 成为连环杀手也是如此
Whatever happened to the hedgehog?
刺猬怎么了?
- What?  - He had to cross the road...
- 什么?  - 他要穿过马路...
and go into the woods, but he was afraid.
进去丛林 但是他害怕
- Harold the Hedgehog?  - Harold the Hedgehog.
- 刺猬哈罗德?  - 对 刺猬哈罗德
Dear little chap. Whatever happened to that story?
可爱的小故事 那个故事后来怎么样了?
- You never finished him.  - He nearly finished me.
- 你都没完结他  - 他差点了结了我
He wrecked my marriage, prickly cunt.
这个多刺的小混蛋 他毁了我的婚姻
No, he did, Clair. I'm sorry, the stress of it.
他就是这么干了 克莱尔 抱歉 这就是重点
Drove Catherine out of my life. What do you wanna talk about him for?
他让凯瑟琳离开了我的生活 你还提他干嘛?
Darling, I'm just thinking you need to earn some money, that's all.
亲爱的 我只是认为你需要赚点钱了 就这样
This death thing could take a while.
写死亡这种事还需要一段时间来完成
Timmy the Tortoise can't pay the bills.
小乌龟蒂姆又不赚钱
I don't want him to. I didn't mean to become a children's author.
我也没想用他付账 我没想要成为儿童作家
- It was a terrible accident.  - It was your destiny.
- 那只是个意外  - 那就是你的命运
Look, why not rattle off a little bedtime story, mm?
听着 为什么不写点床边故事呢 怎么样?
- Timmy goes to the seaside perhaps?  - Oh, God.
- 也许写蒂姆去海滩的故事?  - 天哪
Or Harold. How did it start?
要么写哈罗德 这是怎么开始的?
"Once upon a time, there was a hedgehog called Harold
"从前 有一只小刺猬叫做哈罗德
who lived in a bush."
他住在灌木丛里"
Or Little Johnny Rabbit.
要么就写小兔子约翰尼
The world is dying for another Little Johnny Rabbit.
这个世界肯定会为另一只小兔子约翰尼而倾倒的
Little Johnny Rabbit is dead.
小兔子约翰尼死了
So is Timmy, so is the fucking hedgehog.
蒂姆也死了 刺猬也死了
They're lying in the road, covered in blood. I killed them.
他们横尸马路 躺在血泊之中 我杀了他们
Tell that to the kids.
就这么跟孩子们说
Darling, we're going to make this work.
亲爱的 我们一起来解决
Just try not to worry too much, and take care of yourself.
别太担心了 照顾好自己
You know me better than anyone, Clair.
你比任何人都了解我 克莱尔
Yes, I do. You're a workaholic and you're sensitive.
是的 我知道你是个工作狂 而且很敏感
I don't wanna see you go over the edge like what's-his-name.
我不想看见你像书里的人那样走极端
Clair's concerns about me proved justified.
克莱尔对我的担忧是正确的
Three weeks on and Long Ear's head was playing on my mind.
三个星期过去了 长耳朵的脑袋一直盘旋在我脑海里
Life was hellish,
生活很凶残
but it was just about to get a hell of a lot worse.
日子却越来越糟糕
Come on then, you bastards!
来呀 你这个混蛋!
Aaaaaargh!
啊啊啊啊啊!
My knife.
我的刀呢
Ah!
啊!
You mad bastard.
你这个疯子
Argh!
啊!
Oh, God.
天哪
Oh, I got an hour.
我还有1个小时
The flying eye.
飞行监视器呀
Oh, someone's on the loose.
哎呦 有人逍遥法外了
It was 5:00 when the telephone rang that fateful evening.
那个关键的晚上 电话在五点时响起
Shit, I could...
该死 我能...
Hello?
你们好?
Happy Christmas.
圣诞节快乐
- What do you want?  - We're singing carols.
- 你们想要什么?  - 我们在唱颂歌
Yeah, I can see that.
恩 看得出来
Well, ain't you gonna come out and hear us then, bruv?
大叔 你不出来听我们唱歌吗?
No, I can hear you perfectly well from up here. Thank you.
不了 我在这就能听到 谢了
We've been out for ages and no one's given us nuffink yet.
我们出来很久了 不过没人给我们吃的
Well, honestly, I think you should perhaps work on your repertoire.
老实说 我觉得你们应该多努力表演你们的节目
- Our what?  - Sorry I can't help you. Good night.
- 我们的什么?  - 抱歉帮不了你们 晚安
But it's for Save the Children.
这可是为了拯救孩子们
Kids who ain't got no food, Nintendo or nothing, bruv.
那些孩子没有食物 没有游戏 什么都没有呀 大叔
All right, all right. Wait there.
好吧 好吧 等等
- I'm coming down.  - Yes.
- 我马上下来  - 耶
You gonna open up this door, then, or what, bruv?
你会打开门的吧 然后呢 大叔?
Um, I tell you what I'm gonna do.
我告诉你们然后怎么办
I'm gonna put some loose change into this sock
我把一些零钱放在这个袜子里
and then I'm gonna feed it through the letter box.
我把袜子从信箱塞出去
- Did you get that?  - Is it clean?
- 听明白没?  - 袜子干净吗?
- Is it what?  - Is it clean?
- 什么?  - 干净吗?
Is the sock clean, bruv?
袜子是干净的吗 大叔?
Well, it's not box fresh, if that's what you mean.
其实 不是新拆封的 如果你们是这个意思的话
Do you want this money or not?
你们想不想要钱啊?
Oh, God.
天哪
Who are you?
你是谁?
- You there?  - Yes. Yes.
- 还在吗?  - 恩 还在
I just... Stand back, okay? Stand back.
我只是... 往后退 好吧? 后退
Christ, can't you see I'm not in?
天哪 难道你不知道我不在家吗?
Okay. Get ready.
好了 准备好
I'm opening my flap.
我要开信箱了噢
Here it comes. Gently does it.
来了 轻点拿
Gently.
轻点
God in heaven, will you just fuck off and give me some peace?
我的神啊 你就不能滚开 让我清净清净?
Hey, wait. Just come back!
嘿 等等 快回来!
Oi! What about my sock? You little thieving, you...
啊! 我的袜子怎么办? 你们这些小偷 你们...
You... you did this.
你们... 你们居然这样
You wanna hear my voice, you sick fuck?
你想听听我的声音吗 你这个变态?
Hear this.
听着吧
- Hello?  - Jack, it's Clair.
- 喂?  - 杰克 我是克莱尔
Hello?
喂?
- Jack, it's Clair.  - Clair.
- 杰克 我是克莱尔  - 克莱尔啊
Why haven't you been answering? I've been calling for hours.
你为什么总不接电话? 我都打了几个小时了
- I thought you were a wrong number.  - Well, listen.
- 我以为是打错的  - 好吧 听着
I've just had a very excited man on the phone.
我刚刚和一个很激动的男人讲完电话
- Have you?  - Yes. He's read your treatment...
- 是吗?  - 恩 他读了你的作品...
for "Decades of Death" and he's very excited by your ideas.
那份"死亡年代" 他对你的构思很感兴趣
He wants to meet you tonight at eight o'clock.
他今晚八点想见见你
Oh.
哦
- I see. Eight o'clock?  - He's off to New York tomorrow.
- 我知道了 8点?  - 他明天要去纽约
- It's imperative you see him.  - Why is it imperative?
- 你势必得见他一面  - 为什么必须见?
Because he's Harvey Humphries.
因为他是哈维·汉弗莱斯
- Harvey Humphries? Who's he?  - Head of scripts.
- 哈维·汉弗莱斯? 他是谁?  - 出版界的领头人物
Clair, look, can I see him when he comes back from New York?
克莱尔 我能不能等他从纽约回来再见面?
Because I've not been sleeping very well and...
因为最近我睡得不太好...
Jack, he's genuinely excited. The arrangements have all been made.
杰克 他非常有诚意 时间都安排好了
Tonight, eight o'clock, 100 Humbolt Mews.
今晚8点 洪堡街100号
100 Humbolt Mews, eight...
洪堡街100号 8点...
- That's in one hour and 47 minutes.  - Wear a suit, please.
- 那不就还剩1小时47分钟吗  - 请穿西装来
- I don't have any suits.  - Wear a clean shirt.
- 我没西装  - 那就穿件干净的T恤
They're all dirty. I'm down to my last sock.
衣服都脏了 最后一只袜子都没了
Then you'll have to go to the launderette, won't you?
那你就去自助洗衣店 行吧?
What? A launderette? Are you serious?
什么? 自助洗衣店? 你说真的?
Of course I am. What's the problem?
是呀 有什么问题?
It's just... You're asking a lot, Clair, okay?
只是... 你要求太多了 克莱尔 知道吗?
I don't do launderettes. Never have done, never will.
我从来不去自助洗衣 以前不会 将来也不会
It's no place for a man like me.
那地方不适合我这样的男人
Exposing your most intimate articles in front of strangers.
怎么能把最私密的物品展露在陌生人面前
- Stop it, you're being ridiculous.  - You know me, Clair. I'm sensitive.
- 闭嘴 你太搞笑了  - 你了解我的 克莱尔 我很敏感
- I've never even bought toilet roll.  - All right, enough.
- 我甚至都不买成卷的厕纸  - 行了 够了吧
Jack, I've worked very hard getting your script to the right people
杰克 我一直很尽力地把你的手稿给合适的人看
and I'm afraid there's no interest.
恐怕没人有兴趣
I said nothing because I didn't want to disturb you. That's the reality.
我什么都没说是因为不想打扰你写作 但这就是事实
I can't see any other options.
我只能说 你别无选择
It's Humphries or bust.
要么去见汉弗莱斯 要么破产
- I understand.  - Good.
- 明白了  - 很好
Call and let me know how it goes, darling.
打电话告诉我事情进展 亲爱的
And so it was that I first came to hear the name Harvey Humphries.
这是我第一次听到哈维·汉弗莱斯的名字
I had sat in every head of scripts department in London,
我曾经拜访过伦敦每一家出版社的头儿
listening to these twats full of white wine and arugula,
听这些吃饱喝足了的笨蛋们讲话
but I had never heard of this man.
但我从来没听过这个人的名字
"Harvey Humphries of Humbolt Mews."
"洪堡街的哈维·汉弗莱斯"
I didn't like the sound of it.
我不喜欢这个发音
The name seemed innocent enough, but there was something that jarred.
这个名字看起来很天真 内里却很刺耳
It might be the "Harvey Humphries Humbolt" bit that was worrying me.
可能是"洪堡街的哈维·汉弗莱斯"让我感觉不爽吧
But I had a friend, Garry Gordon in Garrick Street.
不过我有个朋友 住在格里克大街的盖里戈登
And he'd never caused me any problem.
他就从来没让我感到不舒服过
No.
不
It was something stronger than just a repetition of the H.
并不是简单的连续H字头
It was more a sensation of having heard Harvey Humphries
感觉更像是从一个臭名昭彰的角度
in some unsavory context.
听过哈维·汉弗莱斯的名字
Harvey.
哈维
It was the Harvey.
是那个哈维
Harvey was the middle name of Dr. Hawley Harvey Crippen,
哈维是霍利·哈维·克里平医生的中间名
the Yank Who'd spent all night in the basement
那个住在N5区 新月希尔德劳普大街39号
of 39 Hilldrop Crescent, N5 separating his wife.
花了一整夜在地下室分尸自己妻子的那个人
He'd done her in lime.
他用石灰泡着她
Crippen had come from America.
克里平是从美国来的
Humphries was going to America within hours
汉弗莱斯在见过我之后
of completing his business with me.
没几个小时也要到美国去
Was Humphries related to Crippen?
汉弗莱斯和克里平有关系吗?
Far-fetched as it might seem to others, it was not impossible.
有点牵强 并不是不可能
Crippen was an American. Yes.
克里平是美国人 对
And so was Humphries.
而且汉弗莱斯也是
Surely it was more than a coincidence that a man going to America
一个马上去美国的人会被这个是叫做"死亡年代"的题目所吸引
should be excited by a title like "Decades of Death"
这一切肯定不仅仅是个巧合
and have the middle name of one of the most famous killers of the lot.
而且还和最著名凶手的中间名一样
No.
不
No, no, no.
不 不 不
Facts like that are beyond the realm of coincidence.
这样的事实绝不仅仅是巧合
Hello? Who's there?
喂? 你是哪位?
Speak up, I can't hear you.
大点声 我听不见
Oh, no. Clair's not here just now.
哦 没有 克莱尔现在不在
This is Irene.
我是艾琳
You want what?
你要什么?
Harvey Humphries. Do you know of a man called Harvey Humphries?
哈维·汉弗莱斯 你认识叫哈维·汉弗莱斯的人吗?
Think carefully before you answer, please.
仔细想好再回答 谢谢
- A man's life may be at stake.  - Oh, I'll have to think about this.
- 性命攸关  - 哦 那我也考虑考虑
Er, hold on a minute, love. Now...
呃 等等 亲爱的 现在...
Can you tell her to call Jack back regarding Harvey Humphries?
你能让她就哈维·汉弗莱斯的事情给杰克打回来吗?
Tell her it's a matter of life and death.
告诉她是性命攸关的大事
- Life and death?  - Yes. Tell her that exactly.
- 性命攸关?  - 对 一字不差的告诉她
- Thank you.  - Right. Will do, dear.
- 谢谢  - 好的 一定转达 亲爱的
Okay, okay. Be rational, be rational.
好的 好的 冷静 冷静
Clair was obviously not in her office, so she must've telephoned you from home.
克莱尔不在办公室 所以她肯定是从家给你打电话的
But as you don't have her private number,
可是因为你没有她的私人号码
and she's ex-directory, there's no way you can call her back.
而且她也不在号码记录上 你没办法给她打回去
I have to trust it was Clair, and that she meant no malice.
我只能相信刚才打电话的就是克莱尔 而且她没有恶意
After all, she has no reason to wish me any harm.
毕竟 她没理由想让我受伤害
She had no way of knowing a man related to a murderer.
她不可能认识一个与凶案有关的人
Only a highly suspicious, paranoid cynic...
只有生性多疑 偏执妄想的愤青...
Or someone like me, with an eye for clues and patterns
或是像我一样 有双能发觉蛛丝马迹的慧眼
could possibly connect the dots.
能把每个疑点都联系起来
Could see the truth staring him in the face.
看到他真人便知道真相
That Harvey Humphries is in fact Hawley Harvey Crippen's grandson.
事实上哈维·汉弗莱斯就是霍利·哈维·克里平的孙子
No more questions, Your Honor.
没问题了 法官大人
Ah!
啊!
Right. That does it.
好了 我可受够了
Where's the superglue?
万能胶在哪?
Right. You've done nothing but terrorise me for weeks.
这呢 你们除了恐吓我好几个礼拜还能做什么
And I've had enough. I've had enough.
我受够了 彻底受够了
Take that, and that, and that, and that.
吃胶水吧 吃啊 吃啊 吃啊
Take that, take this, take this.
给我粘住 粘住 粘住
Take that. You didn't expect that, did you?
粘牢你 你没想到吧?
Well, expect the unexpected, mate.
学会接受现实吧 伙计
God, that's quick.
天哪 这么快就粘牢了
Hello? Anyone home?
您好? 有人在家吗?
Yes? Hello?
在啊 怎么了?
Are you the gentleman in Flat 3?
您是住在3单元的先生吗?
Who is this?
你是谁?
Community Support Police Officer Perkins, sir.
我是社区支援警官珀金斯 先生
Good evening. How can I help you?
晚上好 找我有什么事吗?
Oh, no cause for alarm. Just a routine call, sir.
哦 别紧张 只是个例行询问 先生
Some of the kids over on the estate said you might be in some distress.
社区里的几个孩子说你好像很痛苦
How interesting.
真有意思
And what might I be distressed about?
他们说我为什么痛苦呢?
Well, I have no idea, sir.
我不知道 先生
Are you in any distress?
您痛苦吗?
No, I'm fine. I'm about to do some washing and then go to bed.
没有 我很好 我正要洗衣服然后去睡觉
Oh, well. Just so you know,
哦 好吧 那跟您说声
we're out on the beat if you ever need assistance.
如果您需要帮助 我们就在外面巡逻
I'm just across the road.
我就在马路对面
Jesus Christ.
天啊
Sorry, sir, sorry. Sorry. I was just checking you were...
对不起 先生 对不起 我只想确认下您没事...
Yeah, well, I'm very sorry to bother you, sir.
很抱歉打扰您 先生
Er, I'll let you get back to your laundry.
您快去洗衣吧
Policeman, my ass.
警察 去他大爷的
He was looking for something.
他刚才在找东西
What was he up to?
他到底来干吗?
Jesus, nowhere's safe.
天哪 没地方是安全的
Okay, Humphries, you want my script? You can have it.
好吧 汉弗莱斯 你想要我的剧本? 我都给你
If it means I finally get paid decent money
如果最后我能拿到合理的报酬
and get out of Hackney, you're on.
搬出哈克尼区 你会拿到剧本的
Right. Where's my wardrobe?
好了 我的行头呢?
I'll show you, Clair, I'll show you, Catherine,
我要让你看看 克莱尔 我要让你看看 凯瑟琳
exactly what I am capable of. Oh!
让你们知道我有多厉害 哦!
Jesus Christ.
我的天哪
God. These aren't clothes, this is refuse.
上帝啊 这哪里是衣服 都成了垃圾
I might as well take it and dig it in around the roses.
我最好拿上它们 埋在玫瑰旁边
I'd do anything for a break right now, but not the launderette.
我现在就想休息会 才不想去洗衣房
Not for Humphries, not for any other man.
不想为了汉弗莱斯 更不想为其他人去洗衣房
Why should I? I've got everything I need here.
为什么非要去洗衣房? 我已经有我需要的全部东西
I've got water, I've got soap, I've got drying facilities.
我有水 有肥皂 我还有烘干机
I can do this, Jack.
我可以洗好的 杰克
No more sleepless nights, no more scuttling around in the dark.
不再有失眠的夜晚 不再在黑暗中沉沦
We'll meet this monster head-on. Well-armed and well-dressed.
我要装备齐全 穿戴整齐的迎头直面那个恶魔
A quick thrash in the tub for you, my lovelies, then into the drier.
迅速在浴盆打个滚后 我的小可爱们 再到烘干机里待会
Right. A good 15 minutes on regular nine for the socks,
总共要十五分钟 袜子烘九分钟
five minutes less for the pants, and we'll play the shirt by ear.
内裤四分钟 衬衣就看情况再定吧
Now, that's cooking with gas.
十分有效率
Here's how to play it. When you get to the meeting, refuse to sit down.
计划是这样 跟他会面的时候 不要坐下
Refuse all drinks and cigarettes. Certainly all food.
婉拒所有的饮料和香烟 食物也一样
The meeting will be conducted standing up.
站着会面就好
And if he leaves the room to make a call, you go with him.
如果他出去打电话 就要跟着他
I'll have a pretext for everything.
我有一个万能的借口
I could take an apple or an onion into the meeting.
我要带个苹果或洋葱去见面
Yeah, that'd work.
这样就好办了
I could use it as a circumstance to show him my carving knife.
我可以据此创造出向他亮出雕刻刀的场景
Ah! Ah!
啊! 黏住了!
Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah!
哎呀! 啊!
Argh!
惨了!
Come on. Come on, come on.
拜托 快点啊 快下来吧
Aow!
啊!
Fuck. What the fuck am I supposed to do now?
妈的 我现在该怎么办?
Cut my fucking hand off?
把手割下来吗?
That's correct, officer.
对了 找警官
When I saw the knife, I simply defended myself with the ice pick.
当我看到刀子的时候 我只是用碎冰锥来自卫
I have no idea how the pick got stuck in the back of his neck.
我不知道锥子是怎么插进他的后颈的
I put him in the bath tub because the blood was staining my Persian carpet.
我把他放进了浴缸里 因为血弄脏了我的波斯地毯
Oh!
哦!
Argh!
啊!
Oh! Oh!
I'm not dead yet, you bastards.
我还没死呢 你个混蛋
Come on, Jack, we can still do this.
走吧 杰克 我们依旧可以做到
Against the odds, we can beat them.
迎难而上 我们能打倒他们
Now, as I remember, this thing has some seriously deep pockets.
我记得 这衣服有很深的口袋
Oh, yeah, yeah. Yeah, I can hide a knife in there.
哦 是的 我可以把刀子藏在这
That's like Loch Ness in there.
这好像有尼斯湖水怪在里面
You could hide a whole submarine in there if you wanna.
你甚至可以把整只水怪藏在这里
I'll just keep my coat on. My hand on my ha'penny.
我要一直穿着外套 把手放在兜里铜板上
Okay, don't let this guy psyche you out, all right?
好了 别让此人搞得你六神无主 知道吗?
You're a writer, Jack, remember?
你是个作家 杰克 记住了吗?
You can just outwit this two-bit Hollywood gangster.
你可以智取那个微不足道的好莱坞流氓
Gangster?
流氓?
Say she didn't throw it away. Please, please, please.
但愿她没把它扔掉 拜托 拜托 拜托
Be in here. Be in here, be in here.
可得在这里啊 在这里 在这里
Where are you? Where are you?
你在哪呢?
"Uzilicious". My definitive gangsta rap compilation.
"由兹里血丝" 我的限量版帮匪说唱磁带
Yeah, yeah.
太棒咯
I remember I wooed Catherine with this shit.
我记得我就用它追求的凯瑟琳
Hope it still works.
希望它没坏
Good times, old friend. Good times.
真好啊 老朋友 想起从前好时光
If you can get me through college, you can get me through anything.
你助我大学顺利毕业 你更会保佑我诸事顺利
# I drop a old-school beat. #
# 让我来段校园摇滚吧 #
# Yeah, yeah. #
# 耶 耶 #
# Yeah, you wanna read my script, bitch? #
# 你想看我剧本吗 婊子? #
# You wanna polish my script? You wanna polish my script? #
# 你想完善我的剧本? 你想翻拍我的剧本? #
# Is that what you're saying? #
# 是你说的吧? #
# What's up, bitch? You wanna polish my script? #
# 怎么了 贱人? 你想改编我的剧本? #
# Oh, sure. Polish this, motherfucker. #
# 好啊 那就看招吧 混蛋 #
# I'm gonna step up to a man called Humphries #
# 我要走到汉弗莱斯这男人面前 #
# Wipe that shit up just like cream cheese #
# 像擦掉奶油芝士一样轻易干掉那个贱人 #
# Up all night, y'all, workin' the mic, y'all #
# 整夜都不睡 伙计们 唱起来 伙计们 #
# Smoking my pipe, y'all, motherfucker #
# 让我抽根烟 伙计们 他是个混蛋 #
# Catherine, this Jam goes out to you. #
# 凯瑟琳 这首摇滚唱给你 #
# It's real, true dat from the heart. #
# 这是我心底真情留白的录音 #
# I just wanna say you're my girl. #
# 我想说你是我的女孩 #
- Shut up.  - # And I love you. #
- 别唱了  - # 还有我爱你 #
Fuck.
妈的
Who are you trying to fool, Jack? You're not a G-man, you're a tit.
你想骗谁呀 杰克? 你又不是联邦调查局的 你就是个窝囊废
What's that smell?
什么味道?
Smells like burning garbage.
闻起来像烧着的垃圾
No! Not the socks! Not the socks!
不! 可别是袜子! 别是我的袜子!
Argh! Damn it!
啊! 该死的!
Oh!
哦!
Oh! Oh, my eyes!
哦! 哦 我的眼睛!
Oh, God, the pants have gone up.
哦 天啊 裤子都烧没了
And you'll have to go to the launderette, won't you?
你该去洗衣房了吧?
- A launderette, are you serious?  - Of course I am.
- 洗衣房 你没开玩笑?  - 我是认真的
You'll have to go to the launderette, won't you?
你只能去洗衣房了 不是吗?
You'll have to go to the launderette.
你必须去洗衣房
Argh!
啊!
Okay, let's cut the cake.
好了 切蛋糕吧
Dad, can you answer that? It's Mr. Goofy. He's lost.
爸爸 你能接电话吗? 是古菲先生 他迷失了
Mr. Goofy is on my office line?
古菲先生往我办公室打电话?
Right, here we go.
好 我们开切
Hello. This is Dr. Friedkin.
你好 我是弗莱德金医生
You've got to help me, Dr. Friedkin.
你得帮帮我 弗莱德金医生
Jack? Is this Jack?
杰克啊? 你是杰克吗?
I can't take it anymore. I'm gonna buckle, I swear to God.
我再也受不了啦 我发誓 我就要死了
Well, it's my grandson's birthday.
可今天是我孙子的生日
A phobia of launderettes?
洗衣房恐惧症?
Oh, Jack. That's a new one to me.
哦 杰克 我真没听说过
Wait, I'm confused. Which case study is this?
等下 我糊涂了 这病源自哪个案例研究?
It's not a case, Dr. Friedkin. It's me.
这不是案例 弗莱德金医生 是我的症状
I'm the problem. It's me.
我有问题 是我
Okay, okay, calm down. Just calm yourself.
好 冷静点 让自己保持镇定
Jack, I want you to take a deep breath.
杰克 我要你先做个深呼吸
Now, inhale...
现在 吸气...
and exhale. That's right.
再呼气 很好
Fill your entire body.
让氧气充满全身
Imagine every cell being rinsed clean with life-giving oxygen.
想象着每个细胞都被让我们生存的氧气冲洗
Do you have any clues where the origin of this phobia lies?
你知不知道这回的恐惧症是怎么引发的?
I've had it all my life.
我一生都有这病
I've tried to get on top of it.
我试着去驾驭恐惧
I went to a washhouse when I was at college,
我大学的时候去过洗衣房
but I was just so terrified,
可我实在太怕了
I accidentally trapped my load in an OOO.
我不小心把衣服放进一台OOO里
An OOO?
一台OOO?
Yes. An out of order machine.
对 一台坏了的机器
I was in there with about six months' of unimaginably sensitive material.
之后的六个月 暗无天日 我一直感觉自己还呆在那里
The room gathered round, engineers were called.
房间里到处都是机器
- It was a nightmare.  - No. I sympathize with you.
- 那是场噩梦啊  - 我同情你
As unpleasant as the experience may have been,
就因为你的痛苦经历
it cannot have been traumatic enough to create such a phobia.
才造成了创伤 引发出恐惧症
It's ruining my life.
恐惧症毁了我整个人生
Look, I can help you, but you must be completely honest.
听着 我能帮助你 可你要对我绝对诚实
And you must trust me.
同时你必须信任我
Close your eyes.
闭上眼睛
I want you to take another deep breath
我要你再做一次深呼吸
and imagine you are sitting here with me now in my office
想象自己正坐在我的办公室里
having a consultation.
我在给你治疗
Think of my office like a space capsule.
把我办公室想象成一个太空舱
From here, we can go anywhere in the universe,
从这里 我们可以借由我们想象的力量
in space and time, by the power of our mind.
飞去宇宙中的任何地方 无论时间和空间
To your childhood, to your dreams.
想想你的童年 你的梦想
Can you see the little hedgehog?
你能看见那只小刺猬吗?
Frightened little hedgehog lives in an old hedgerow
受惊的小刺猬就住在教堂旁边的灌木丛里
by the church. Can you see the spider?
你能看见那只蜘蛛吗?
Clever spider. Waiting in the shadows.
聪明的蜘蛛 总在阴暗处中等待着
And Mrs. Ladybird? And Mr. Rabbit?
还有瓢虫夫人? 兔子先生?
How about old farmer...?
看到老农民了吗...?
Did you have a happy childhood?
你的童年快乐吗?
- What is your earliest memory?  - The orphanage on fire.
- 你最早的记忆是什么?  - 孤儿院起火
- You're being facetious.  - No, I'm not, really.
- 你真会说笑  - 我没开玩笑 是真的
The orphanage I was in caught fire. November the 5th, 1979.
我所在的孤儿院着火了 那是1979年11月5日
Somebody let off a Roman candle in the dormitory.
有人在宿舍燃放了一支罗马烟火筒
Luckily no one was hurt.
幸好无人伤亡
You're an orphan? I'm sorry, I didn't...
你是个孤儿? 抱歉 我不知道...
My mother abandoned me when I was 5 years old.
母亲在我五岁时抛弃了我
She just packed a little suitcase for me one day
有一天她给我打包好一个小行李箱
and disappeared.
之后她就消失了
How did it happen, Jack?
为什么会那样 杰克?
- It's all right to feel vulnerable.  - These pyjamas aren't helping.
- 感觉到无助是正常的  - 这些睡衣根本不起作用
Try, Jack.
试试 杰克
Try to go back.
试着回想从前
The only memory I have of my mother is of a book she gave me.
我对母亲的唯一记忆就是她给我的一本书
Fairy tales I suppose you call them. With these awful talking rodents.
你们管它叫童话故事 里面讲的都是讨厌的会说话的啮齿动物
Look, truth is it doesn't bother me.
你看 事实不会让我不安
I don't miss my mother because I don't remember her.
我不想念我母亲因为我不记得她
I just... I'm sick of these irrational fears.
我只是... 受不了那些荒谬的恐惧
Like the bloody launderette. It's stopping me from living my life.
就好像血腥的洗衣店 它阻碍了我的正常生活
Well, you can do something about it. You're not a child anymore.
你可以克服的 你已经不是小孩了
I once treated a girl who had a phobia of bananas.
我曾经治疗过一个有香蕉恐惧症的女孩
When this girl came to me, she was so pleased with herself.
这个女孩在找我看病后 对自己很满意
She'd been able to overcome her phobia
她已经能控制她的恐惧
to the extent that she could sit in the same room as a closed banana.
已经可以跟没剥开香蕉坐在一个房间里
It had to stay closed, unzipped, or else she'd go completely psychotic.
原本只要她接近一根剥开的香蕉 她就会完全疯掉
But the point is, open or closed, she had not made the connection
问题是 无论怎样 她从未把
between her phobia and her fear.
自己害怕的东西和恐惧症联系在一起
- Of bananas?  - No. It was something else.
- 就因为香蕉吗?  - 不 是其他的东西
A past trauma. Something more threatening than a mere banana.
是过去的创伤 是比一根香蕉更恐怖的事情
Do you understand? It's like a movie screen.
你明白吗? 就好像电影屏幕
She projected her fear onto the banana
她把自己的恐惧转移到香蕉上
because looking directly at her trauma was too terrifying.
因为她无法直接面对那太恐怖的创伤经历
It was a projection.
香蕉只是个投影
- Onto a piece of fruit?  - Exactly.
- 投影到了一种水果上?  - 正是
Her banana's no different to your launderette.
她的香蕉正是你的洗衣房
I also have a recurring nightmare about an eyeball.
我总是反复做一个关于眼球的噩梦
- What sort of eyeball?  - The giant, floating kind.
- 什么样的眼球?  - 巨大的 漂浮的那种
Sort of eye of death, watching me.
那种死亡之眼 死死盯着我
All fears and neurosis can be traced back to our early childhood.
所有的恐惧和神经衰弱都可追溯至幼时
To the first terrifying recognition that we are alone in the world.
因为发现自己在这世上孤身一人 便第一次认识到了恐惧
When a young child is abandoned, it has no concept of time.
当一个孩子被抛弃 他就没有了时间概念
No understanding that things can get better.
他不相信一切会变好
That there is hope. For a child, Jack, mother equals life.
毫无希望 对孩子来说 杰克 母亲即是生命
Take away the mother
离开了母亲
and the child is literally swallowed by death.
孩子就同被死亡吞噬没有分别
But I didn't die, did I?
但我没死 不是么?
No. You lived...
是的 你活下来...
to experience your own death.
感受着自己的死亡
That's some scary shit, Dr. Friedkin.
那种感觉真是可怕 弗莱德金医生
It's the primal trauma we are all trying to forget.
这就是我们试着去遗忘的原始的精神创伤
To bury in our subconscious.
我们把它隐埋在潜意识中
But it inevitably finds expression either in dreams or fears
但它却无可避免地出现在梦里或恐惧里
or infantile fantasies.
亦或是在幼时的幻想里
Dad? How much longer are you gonna be in there?
爸爸? 你还要在里面待多久?
Just finishing up, sweet pea. I'm sorry, Jack. We have to end now.
这就好了 小甜豆 我很抱歉 杰克 我们得结束治疗了
I don't know how to thank you, Dr. Friedkin.
真不知道该怎么感谢你 弗莱德金医生
Perhaps as a teenager, you were subliminally drawn to that OOO,
或许在少年时期 你下意识地被000机器吸引了吧
because somewhere deep in your subconscious,
在你的潜意识深处
you recognised that you, too, are out of order.
你认识到 自己也出了差错
Broken. You don't work anymore.
坏掉了 不再灵光了
The primary defence mechanisms you relied on
支持你度过童年的
to get you through childhood no longer support you as an adult.
最主要的心理防御机制 无法在你成年后继续成立
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
You're fucked up, Jack. You need therapy.
你有些混乱 杰克 你需要治疗
I haven't got time. I've got a meeting about an hour.
我没有时间了 我一小时后还有一个会面
Return to the scene of the crime
回到犯罪现场
and retrieve those unwashed articles locked in the machine.
然后找出被锁在机器里那些未清洗过的零件
Release your raw, true, inner self.
释放你真实的本我和内心
Begin a new life, free from fear.
开始新的生活 摆脱恐惧
Fear of death.
对死亡的恐惧
The irony is we must all journey through
讽刺的是我们所有人在到达天堂前
before we can reach our heaven.
都要历经炼狱
Dr. Friedkin, I think it's time I faced my banana.
弗莱德金医生 我觉得是时候去面对我的香蕉了
It's step-up time, yo, motherfucker.
到出发的时候了 混蛋
It's all right, mate. It's all right.
没事的 伙计 我们没事哈
What the fuck?
怎么回事?
Everything all right, sir?
你还好吗 先生?
Yes. Yes, I'm fine, thank you.
是的 我还好 谢谢
- Looks like you're in a hurry.  - Yes, well, I have an appointment.
- 您看起来很急啊  - 是的 我有一个约会
With death.
和死神
- Excuse me?  - I mean, with the launderette.
- 您说什么?  - 我是说 和洗衣店
I'm going to wash some socks.
我要去洗袜子
- There's no crime in that, is there?  - Not that I'm aware of.
- 洗衣店里没有什么犯罪吧?  - 据我所知没有
Good. Well, I'll be on my way, then. Good night.
很好 那我就走了 晚安
Good night.
晚安
Keep it together, keep it together.
勇敢点 勇敢点
It's only a banana. It's not him you're afraid of, it's only...
就是一个香蕉嘛 你怕的不是他 只是个...
Okay. Stick to the plan.
好吧 保持原计划
If I move fast, I can get in and out in half an hour.
如果我动作快 进去半小时就能出来
That leaves 20 minutes to change and get a taxi north.
剩下二十分钟用来换衣服 叫出租车向北走
No room for error.
绝不能出差错
"Everything automatic. One, open the door."
"一切都是自动的 第一步 打开门"
"Two, get the clothes in."
"第二步 把衣服放进去"
"Three, shut the door and have two pound coins ready."
"第三步 关上门 准备好两英镑硬币"
"Four, place the money in the slot."
"四 把钱放入投币口"
"Five, push your slot in."
"五 按下按钮"
Great.
太好了
How do I manage it?
我该怎么控制恐惧?
I've managed to create a bad impression. I'm still in the street.
我已经有了不妙的感觉 可我还在大街上呢
Okay. Okay, you can do this. You can do this.
好了好了 你能做到的 你能做到
Looks like my lucky day.
看来今天是我幸运日
Only four people and no visible infants.
只有四个人 也没看见婴儿
There, look.
在那 快看
The atmosphere's easing a little. I'm blending in.
气氛已经有所缓和 我要进去了
Okay, so far so good. I'm already up to number three.
好的 目前为止都不错 我该进行第三步了
"Shut the door, have two pound coins ready."
"关好门 准备好两镑硬币"
"Four, put the money in. Five..."
"四 把钱放进去 五..."
Shit. These signs are older than the machines.
该死 这些标志比机器还要旧
What do I do now?
我现在该怎么办?
Heavy soil.
选重度污渍
Jesus, it's over.
天啊 终于弄好了
All I have to do is stand in front of it until the things come out clean.
我现在要做的就是站在它前面直到它们全部变干净
I need to check out those drying machines.
我得去看看那些烘干机
Interesting. It appears the technique is to open the door
有意思 看起来技巧就是在干衣服飞过的时候
and grab the dry things as they fly past.
快速打开门把它们拽出来
So more heat gets concentrated into bulkier items such as woollens.
烘干的热量就可以更集中于大件 比如毛料衣服
While at the same time anything fragile
同时还可以避免
are spared unnecessary exposure.
小件的衣服不会暴露
I'll have to remember that for my shirt.
我要注意 我的衬衫也要这么办
Wait.
等等
Something's wrong.
不太对劲
I'm spinning without a problem, but mine's different to the others.
我的操作程序没有错 为什么我的看起来跟其他人的不一样
What is this? I can't afford a hitch.
什么情况? 我不能接受
Excuse me.
请问
- Mine hasn't gone white yet.  - What hasn't?
- 我的还没有变白  - 什么没变白?
My washing water. Look.
洗衣服的水 看
You didn't put no soap in.
你没放洗衣粉
- I thought the machine did it.  - Machine don't put own soap in.
- 我以为机器会自动放的  - 机器不会自动放洗衣粉
You have to put soap in. Where your soap?
你得自己放 你的洗衣粉呢?
I haven't got any. It says everything's automatic.
我没有啊 这不是说全自动吗
See number six, "Add detergent."
看第六条 "添加洗涤剂"
No.
哦不
What am I gonna do?
那我该怎么办?
- It's not gonna get washed, is it?  - Not without soap.
- 这样是洗不干净的 对吧?  - 不放洗衣粉的话 是的
I've done it again. How is it possible
我又搞砸了 怎么可能
to keep putting things into machines without getting them clean?
脏衣服放到机器里 却无法得到干净衣服
Look here. Have you got any soap?
请问 你有洗衣粉吗?
Soap in slot machine one pound.
自动洗衣粉机 一镑一盒
Here, soap.
给 洗衣粉
Thanks.
谢谢
Not now.
现在别放
You cannot put soap in now, you've missed your cycle.
现在不能放洗衣粉 已经错过了
You wait.
你得等着
- Tell me when to put the soap.  - No. I'm in hurry to go home.
- 要放的时候告诉我一下  - 没空 我要回家
So am I.
我也是
You haven't been here since 8:00 this morning.
你可不像我 早上八点就来了
What've you got in there?
你都洗了些什么?
- A shirt and some socks.  - That's it?
- 一件衬衫还有些袜子  - 就这些?
No.
不是
- There's a pair in there as well.  - A pair?
- 还有条底裤  - 一条?
A pair of underpants?
一条内裤?
- That's all you put in machine?  - I'm allowed to, aren't I?
- 你就放了这点东西进去?  - 怎么了 不可以吗?
You can put in a handkerchief for all I care.
你只放个手绢进去我也没意见
But I think it's a criminal waste of water.
但浪费水简直是太可怕了
Sorry. How right you are.
对不起 你说的对
In fact in a funny way, crime is the only reason I'm here.
搞笑点来说 正是由于害怕我才来这里
I'm going home. It's half past seven.
我要回家了 都七点半了
Actually it's 7:20. But if I'd been in here
实际上才七点二十 但是如果
since 8:00, I'd have started lying about more than the time to get out.
我是早上八点就来了 我也愿意把回家的时间说的紧迫点
- We'll miss out the drying.  - Yeah, I agree.
- 好像已经烘干了  - 应该是
I've missed my cycle.
我错过了放洗衣粉的时机
Will it still get clean?
还能洗干净吗?
I'm gonna have to chance it. I'm cutting it fine as it is.
冒险试试看吧 也许凑合能洗干净
And why do I seem to be the only one with a machine
但是为什么只有我的这个洗衣机
that refuses to stop spinning?
一直没完没了地转呢?
Those two are beginning to annoy me.
这两个人让我很困扰
Especially the one in the rollers who looks like Caligula.
尤其是那个重金属版的卡里古拉大帝（罗马的一位暴君）
She's obviously the ring leader.
她肯定是个帮派头目
What the hell are they staring at?
见鬼 他们盯着看什么呢?
I imagine they live pretty mundane lives here
我想她们在这洗衣房里过着
in these launderettes, but even so...
平庸的生活 但即使如此...
It's over. I'm free. Get me out of here.
洗好了 我自由了 我解放了
Oh, no. A beautiful girl.
哦 不 来了个美女（长得跟MJ似的还美女)
That's the last thing I need.
这是我最不想见到的
It's bad enough shifting underwear with these louts.
对着这些俗人把内裤搬来搬去的就够糟了
Now I'm gonna have to do it with her watching.
现在还得当着美女的面这么做
Better be discrete, it's down to the dryers now.
还好没缠一起 现在走向烘干机
I'll just hang back here.
就待在这儿
Hope the beautiful girl doesn't notice my presence.
希望美女别注意到我
She's trying to block my view of her dryer.
她试图挡住我的视线
What does she think I am? A Peeping Tom?
她以为我是什么人? 偷窥狂吗?
Jesus. The size of that. I've never seen anything like it.
上帝啊 瞧那尺寸 没见过这么大的
And another. That thing must have "Dunlop" written on it.
还有一个 这是邓禄普牌的吗?(轮胎品牌)
Oh, thanks. Thanks very much.
行 谢啦 非常感谢
That's just downright impolite.
原谅我的失礼
Listen, darling, I don't wanna look at your fucking underwear.
听着 亲爱的 我不想看你的破内衣
It might excite the gentlemen in your life, but as far as I'm concerned
可能有男人会对那感兴趣 但是对我来说
it's about as sexy as a couple of buckets, which is what it looks like.
那就像俩吊桶一样性感 根本就是两个吊桶
I look like something out of a horror movie.
我看起来像恐怖片里的怪物
All those little ruptured blonde hairs.
我那美丽的金色秀发啊
My head looks like a Swede's scrotum.
我脑袋看起来像个瑞典大阴囊
No wonder they've been watching me. I look horrifying.
难怪他们都看着我 我看起来真恐怖
I'm a monster.
我是个怪物
What to do?
怎么办?
I've still got half an hour.
还有半个小时
I could go to the service station, get some big sunglasses.
我可以去商店 买个大墨镜
Yeah. Yeah.
对 很好
Yeah, it could work.
对 就这么办
Yeah, motherfucker. Hood up.
很好 操他妈的 还有兜帽
Right, I've gotta get out of here. And quick.
行了 我得离开这 尽快
A bit of dampness never hurt anybody.
潮一点没关系的
Forget them. They're lost forever.
忘了它吧 它一去不返了
Just get the sock and the shirt.
赶紧拿袜子和衬衫
Excuse me.
不好意思
Are these yours?
这是你的吗?
No.
不是
No. Nothing to do with me.
跟我没关系
- Are they yours?  - They're his. I saw them come out.
- 是你们的吗?  - 就是他的 我看到了
- Excuse me. What's your name?  - John.
- 请问 你叫什么名字?  - 约翰
- My name is John.  - Then they are yours.
- 我叫约翰  - 那这就是你的
It's embroidered inside on a little tab.
里面标签上有你的名字
Yes. Yes, they are. They are mine, yes.
是 没错 是我的 是我的
Lent them to somebody, long time ago.
借给别人了 好久以前
Not sure how they got into my wash actually.
不知道怎么又跑到洗衣机里去了
- Don't you want them?  - No.
- 你不要了?  - 不要了
No. No, thank you.
不要了 谢谢
- I don't want them.  - Throw them in the bin, love.
- 我也不要啊  - 扔垃圾桶吧 亲爱的
Yes, thank you. You've been very kind.
好的 谢谢 麻烦你啦
Look out. He's got a blade.
小心 他有刀
It's not what it looks like. I'm not gonna hurt anybody. Really.
不是你们想的那样 我不会伤害任何人的 真的
I'm a professional writer. For television. Don't go.
我是职业作家 写电视剧的 别跑啊
- Call the cops!  - Please.
- 报警!  - 不要
- Call the cops!  - No, no. Stop, stop, stop.
- 报警  - 不要 别 别
Argh!
啊!
- Go.  - Get.
- 快跑  - 快
Where's the cops?
警察呢?
Go that way. Take that route, gotta get that next one.
走那边 从那条路 下个路口看看
Half past.
半点过了
I've still got 20 minutes.
还有二十分钟
- Back off.  - Please, I can explain.
- 退后  - 求你了 让我解释一下
- Let me out. I can explain.  - No way. Go on, stay back.
- 让我出去 我可以解释  - 别想 继续 退后
Look, I know I look weird, but I'm a writer.
听着 我知道看起来很怪 我是个作家
I don't normally look like this
平时我不是这样的
and I certainly don't wanna use this knife.
我真的没打算用刀子
Please, I have a really important meeting.
求你了 我有个很重要的约会
Not interested, mate, okay? And I said back off.
没兴趣听你胡扯 我说了退后
There must be another way out of here.
应该还有别的出口
Jen.
珍快来
They're coming. They're coming.
他们来了 警察来了
Hang on, I can hear the sirens.
坚持住 我听到警笛声了
- Hurry up. He's trying to get out.  - Come on, Clair.
- 快点 他想逃跑  - 快接啊 克莱尔
Come on, pick up, pick up. Come on, Clair. Pick up, pick up.
快点 接电话 快点克莱尔 接电话啊
Come on.
快点啊
Oh.
糟了
- You say he threatened you?  - I'll say he's sick as a pig.
- 你说他威胁到你了?  - 我得说他笨的像猪
- Stand by. We got a nutter.  - Hurry. He's trying to get away.
- 待命 是个疯子  - 快点 他要逃掉了
Okay, stand back.
好的 退后
Roger. About to apprehend said knife man. Over.
注意 拘捕一名持刀疑犯
Positions.
就位
Follow. Follow. Follow.
快 快 快
- I'm in.  - Right.
- 我进来了  - 很好
- Yeah.  - I can't see him.
- 好的  - 没看到他
Dryers clear, sarge. Dryers clear.
烘干机安全 长官 烘干机安全
No visuals. No visuals. No visuals.
未发现目标 未发现目标
- Where is he?  - Is this the right launderette?
- 他在哪?  - 是这间洗衣房吗?
- Covered.  - Stay still!
- 掩护  - 不许动!
What should I do? Come on, stay still!
该怎么做? 快点 不许动!
All right, sonny. Drop the knife.
好了 小子 放下刀
Now. Drop the knife. Step forward.
立即放下刀 走过来
Hands up where we can see them!
举起手来
I'm not here to hurt anybody.
我无意伤害任何人
I'm a professional writer.
我是个职业作家
Drop the knife, don't give me no mumbo.
放下刀 别胡言
- Mumbo?  - Mumbo jumbo.
- 胡言?  - 胡言乱语
- Well, it's stuck.  - You heard. Drop it.
- 可是 粘住了  - 听到没 放下刀
We want the knife, bitch.
把刀放下 混蛋
- Be my guest.  - Tase him.
- 帮我个忙  - 电他
This way please, sir.
这边走 先生
All right back off, sonny, back off. Out of the way.
好了 让开路 小子 让开 让开路
Help him get that off. I can't take him anywhere with that.
给他把那玩意弄下来 我可不能就这样带他走
Okay, this way, sir.
好的 这边走 长官
Sir, you do not have to say anything.
先生 你可以保持沉默
Anything you do say may be given in evidence.
你说的每句话将会作为呈堂证供
He wants locking up, that boy.
他应该进监狱 那小子
- Lock him up.  - It's not me you should be after.
- 把他拷起来  - 你不该怪我
It's this bastard in North London, Harvey...
要怪就怪伦敦北部那些混混 哈维...
- That's blinding.  - All right.
- 太刺眼了  - 好吧
Filming for "Beat Cops", mate. It's gonna be on TV.
" 挑战警察"摄制组的 是个电视剧
Anything you wanna say?
你想说点什么吗?
No. Go away. This is my life. This is not some excuse for cheap TV.
没 滚开 这是我的生活 不是什么低成本电视剧的桥段
- Aow!  - You're being very brave.
- 疼!  - 勇敢点
Bugger off. You got what you want.
快消失 该拍都拍了
Sarge, look, I set fire to myself before I came out
长官 我出门前不小心自焚了一下
then I glued this knife to my hand.
又不小心把刀粘在手上了
- You threatened the ladies.  - I didn't.
- 你威胁了那几位女士  - 我没有
- They say you did.  - I really didn't.
- 他们说你有  - 这个真没有
Please, can you tell them. I didn't, did I?
求你了 跟他们呢说说 我没威胁你们吧
No. He just sort of got it out.
不 他只是把刀抽了出来
He can tell us all about it down the station.
到了局里再解释吧
- Right. He is done.  - Okay, everyone.
- 好了 去掉了  - 各位
It's over. Go back to your homes.
没事了 各回各家
Safety has been restored.
你们安全了
- Thank you, everyone.  - See you later.
- 感谢各位  - 回头见
- Load him up.  - Wait. I'm innocent.
- 上车  - 等等 我是无辜的
Look, I've got a meeting this evening. Tell him I'm safe.
听着 今天晚上我有个重要约会 跟她说我是好人
Enough or I'll do you for resisting arrest.
老实点 不然算你拒捕
I'm a victim of circumstance.
我是无辜受害者啊
All units, Mare Street. Go. Go. Go.
全体注意 梅尔大街 快 快 快
- Sarge?  - Little Vietnam, big trouble.
- 长官?  - 小越南仔们 惹大麻烦了
What do we do with Paddington?
这家伙怎么办?
- Take him. Chuck him in the van.  - Hey, no way. I've got a meeting.
- 带上他 关进车厢  - 嘿 别这样 我还有个约会
Come on, then! Shake a leg!
快点 快点 动作快!
Follow that chopper!
跟着直升机
- Oh, for Pete's sake.  - Mirror, signal, manoeuvre.
- 搞什么呢  - 一灯二档三喇叭没学过吗
Shut up! I am driving this truck.
闭嘴! 是老娘在开车
Looks like they let you go after all.
看起来最后他们还是把你放了
You're free.
你自由了
Free.
自由
It's fate.
命运啊
I'm facing my demons.
我直面心中的魔鬼
And I'm winning.
我赢了
I'm free.
我自由了
Come on, stars! Give me your best shot.
来吧 小星星! 为我而闪烁吧
I'm ready.
我准备好了
Let's do this.
没问题了
Oops.
噢
- Evening, sir.  - Sorry, officer.
- 晚上好 先生  - 对不起 警官
- Something funny, sir?  - No, I'm just happy.
- 有什么好笑的 先生?  - 不是 我只是高兴
Happy? Are you drunk, sir?
高兴? 你喝酒了 先生?
- No, I'm a writer.  - Oh, yeah?
- 不 我是个作家  - 是吗?
I'm on my way to meet a Hollywood movie mogul actually.
实际上我正要去见个来自好莱坞的大人物
- You're kidding?  - He's very interested...
- 你开玩笑吧?  - 他很有兴趣...
in buying my script about serial killers.
买我的关于连环杀手的剧本
You don't say. Are you all right? Did you get your laundry done?
真的假的 你没事吧? 衣服都洗好啦?
No. Maybe another night.
没有 回头再说吧
Oh, well. Well, good night then, miss.
哦 好的 晚安 小姐
Night, sir.
晚安 先生
You must return to the scene of the crime
回到让你恐惧的地方去
and retrieve those unwashed articles in the machine.
从洗衣机里拿出那些脏东西
Release your raw, true, inner self.
释放你原始的 真实的 内心的自我
Begin a new life, free from fear.
重新感受生命 不再恐惧
Okay. Okay, I got this.
好的 我做到了
Dr. Friedkin, one banana signed, peeled and...
弗莱德金医生 我搞定了我的香蕉...
Huh?
嗯?
- Oh, my God, what happened?  - I don't know.
- 发生了什么事?  - 不知道
How do we get out of here?
怎么逃出去?
Oh, my God, what happened? How did we get here?
天哪 怎么了? 我们怎么在这里?
I was walking down the road.
我在路上走着呢
Yeah, I was walking down the alley and I heard a noise and...
没错 我走在巷子里 然后听到些声音然后...
Oh, God, I feel sick.
我好害怕
Oh, my God. I have to let my parents know I'm here.
我得让爸妈知道我在这里
They'll panic, they'll panic. I don't want them to panic.
他们会着急的 他们会害怕 我不想让他们害怕
What's that?
什么?
You're gonna heave?
你想吐?
- You can't leave?  - I can't breathe.
- 你想离开?  - 我无法呼吸
Oh, you can't breathe. I'm so sorry.
噢 你无法呼吸 对不起
Thank you.
谢谢
They must have drugged us and dumped us here.
他们肯定是给我们灌了药 然后把我们丢在这里
Who? Who did this?
谁? 谁做的?
The Vietnamese mafia. Think about it. We're still in the launderette.
越南黑手党 想想吧 我们还在洗衣店里
It's some sort of safe house. They caught me snooping and thought,
这是个地下室什么的 他们肯定跟踪了我 研究过我的
- "Let's tie him up and dump him."  - Oh, my God.
- "捆起来 丢在这里"  - 天哪
No, no, no. It doesn't add up. It doesn't add up at all.
不对 不对 这不成立 完全不成立
They might have suspected me, but you were no threat whatsoever.
他们可能监视了我 但不会对你这么做的
What are you saying?
你说什么呢?
It must've been premeditated. We've been abducted by a psychopath
这是有预谋的犯罪 我们被疯子绑架了
whose intention is to terrorise, torture and terminate our existence.
他的目的就是虐待 折磨 弄死我们
- No.  - What do you mean, no?
- 不  - 什么不?
No, I refuse to believe that. What about mistaken identity, huh?
不 我拒绝接受你的说法 会不会认错人了?
This could all be a practical joke.
说不定其实是开玩笑呢
A joke? Are you out of your mind?
玩笑? 你傻了吗?
No, you're paranoid. You're jumping to conclusions.
不 你疑心太重了 不能这么草率的下结论
There is a time and place for accusing a man of being paranoid.
回头再慢慢指责一个男人是不是多疑了
This is not fucking one of them!
现在可没那闲工夫!
- Help! Help us, please!  - Help, please!
- 救命! 救救我们!  - 救命!
'Help! Help us, please! 'Help! Help, please!
救命啊! 救救我们 救命救命
- Please!  - Somebody, help us!
- 有人吗!  - 谁来救救我们!
Listen.
听
Somebody's up there.
上面有人
What do we do?
怎么办?
Mummy.
妈呀
Hello?
有人吗?
- What's going on down here, then?  - Oh, mate.
- 这里发生什么事了?  - 噢 朋友
Are you all right?
你们没事吧?
Mate, I have never been so happy to see a...
朋友 我简直太高兴了 你是...
- Community support police officer.  - Community support police officer.
- 社区治安协警  - 对 社区治安协警
Quickly untie us. Come down, please.
快来放开我们 下来 快点
No. Shit. No. Don't. Go back up. Get some help.
别 该死 别下来 去找支援 找人来帮忙
- Get some backup.  - Right.
- 去找支援  - 好吧
We're trapped. We are trapped.
我们被困住了 我们被困住了
- He can see that.  - Don't leave us!
- 他看得到  - 别离开我们
If they come back, they'll get him too.
要是坏人回来了 他也会被抓住的
- He's police.  - He's not even armed.
- 他是警察  - 他没武器
They haven't even given him a fucking whistle.
他连个该死的哨子都没有
Listen, mate, go and get some help.
听着 哥们 去找人来帮忙
Get some men with guns and the dogs.
找些人来 带上枪 还有狗
And some dogs with guns and a fucking helicopter. Just go. Go.
带着枪的狗 还有直升机 快去 快
On second thought, I think I'll just stay here with you.
想想 我还是跟你待在这里吧
Very cosy. Just the three of us.
挺好的 就咱三个
The criminal stare.
犯罪视角
What's he doing?
他干嘛?
I'm afraid this is one very sick community support police officer.
我想这是个变态的社区治安协警
Very good.
很好
You know, you can't beat these old machines for sheer craftsmanship.
知道嘛 这种老机器真是无与伦比
Front loading, motor power, elegant design.
前开门 大功率 造型简洁
Admittedly, they don't spin as fast as modern machines do,
虽然 不像新产品洗得那么快
but so what?
那又怎么样?
As Mahatma Gandhi said, "There's more to life
圣雄甘地曾经说过 " 除了单纯的追求速度"
than simply increasing its speed."
生命还有更大的意义"
Looking at this washing machine, you'd have to agree with him.
看着这洗衣机 你们不得不同意这话
I mean, it's a bloody work of art.
我是说 这就是件艺术品啊
I said, it's a work of art. Don't you agree?
我说 这是件艺术品 你们同意吗?
Yes, it's very nice.
是 它非常棒
Right, well, take comfort in that,
很好 好好看两眼吧
because it's the last thing you're gonna see before you die.
因为这将是你们此生见的最后一件东西了
If you both look closely, you'll notice a pea green flashing light.
要是你们仔细看看 可以看到一个绿灯在闪
Which means, that while you were both sleeping
这意味 你们酣睡的时候
this machine has already passed smoothly
这台洗衣机已经悄悄的
through the stages of pre-wash and main wash
完成了预洗和洗涤的程序
and is now completing the last rinse.
现在正在完成最后一次漂洗
Ow.
噢
This will shortly be followed by the magnificent final spin
很快就会进行最后一次华丽地脱水
at which point, the cycle will end, the light will turn red...
然后 衣服洗好了 显示灯也红了...
and I shall have the pleasure of sending you both to a better
我就可以把你们俩送到一个更美好
and, one would hope, cleaner world than this.
更干净的世界
You fucking maniac.
你这个疯子
I was just gonna go home and catch some telly.
我本来都要下班回家看电视了
But when you mentioned you were a writer, about serial killers,
突然想起你说你是写连环杀手的小说家
I thought, "No. No, this is meant to be.
我想 "不会这么走运吧"
"This is fate."
"根本就是命运安排我们相遇"
- What do you call yourself?   - What's that?
- 你叫什么?  - 什么叫什么?
What do you call yourself? The Spin King? Laundry Man?
你在杀手界的名号是什么? 分尸王? 还是洗衣店杀手?
No, I'm the Hanoi Handshake. That's me.
江湖人称河内友谊大使  正是在下
After I kill you, I'm going to chop your fingers off
杀了你之后 我要把你的手指单独砍下来
and pin it on the Vietnamese lot.
然后一根根钉在越南的土地上
WW? Why are you doing this?
什么? 你为什么要这样
Oh, well, it's complicated.
嗯 原因很复杂
You see, this launderette used to belong to my grandmother.
你不知道 这家洗衣店以前是我奶奶开的
That is, before the whole neighbourhood went to Pot.
可是 后来那些邻里们都去波特那家店洗衣服了
Pol Pot.
波尔波特洗衣店
No, the boat people elbowed her out. Broke her heart. Killed her.
他们这样拒绝我奶奶 伤透了她的心 她就这么走了
So I'm on a rampage, a rampage of vengeance.
我很生气 我想要报复
Oh, I see.
看出来了
Anyway, that's not important now.
不过 那些都不重要了
What is important
目前你们要关心的是
is that I've got the key, and no one knows we're here.
钥匙在我这里 而且没有人能救得了你们
So then, if you don't mind, I've just got to quickly go upstairs
放心 我先上楼 等等就回来
and sharpen my knife.
我去磨磨刀
Sit tight, kids.
安分点 同志们
And remember, when the light goes red,
哦 提醒一句 灯变红的时候
you're dead.
就是我送你们下地狱的时候
Hm, the rinse is ending.
喂 洗衣机快要结束漂洗了
Oh, that's it then, isn't it?
哇 就这样了 是吧?
Not only am I not gonna make my meeting with Harvey Humphries,
我不仅要失约 见不到哈维·汉弗莱斯
I'm gonna fucking die.
我还要去死了
Hey, stop it.
不要再大呼小叫了
You mustn't lose hope.
你不能现在就绝望啊
There's no hope. We're dead.
我们逃不出去了 我们马上要死了
There is always hope.
总是有办法的
I was abandoned in a launderette as a child.
小时候我就是在洗衣店被抛弃的
I couldn't speak for six weeks, I was so afraid.
那时候太害怕了 我连续六周说不出一句话
I've come full circle.
命运给我开了个玩笑
I'm alive,
那时我活下来了
alive to experience my own death.
居然是为了活着等死
It's destiny.
逃不过了 这是命
No!
救命!
No! No! No!
来人啊! 救命!
Listen, your mother, she gave up on herself, not on you.
听着 你妈妈 她抛弃的是自己 不是你
You don't make the same mistake.
你不要犯同样的错误
We can do it together.
现在我们一块想办法
Come on, we have to try and reason with him.
听着 我们要想办法劝他不要杀我们
There's always hope.
我们可以的
I don't even know your name.
我还不知道你叫什么
Sangeet. My name is Sangeet.
我叫做桑吉特
Sangeet.
桑吉特
That's a very beautiful name.
真好听
Sangeet, do you think if all this blows over,
桑吉特 要是我们能逃过这劫
you and I might perhaps get some dinner or...?
我们能一起吃个饭之类的吗...?
That's the spirit, John.
好主意 约翰
Hey.
哎
Call me Jack.
还是叫我杰克吧
Those about to die, we salute you.
让我们向死亡致敬
What's wrong? Not your cup of tea?
为什么不鼓掌? 你不喜欢?
But how can you not like this?
你居然不喜欢这首歌?
This is top-notch. This is classic rock.
当年这首歌红遍大江南北 堪称摇滚乐的经典啊
Er, no.
不是吧
Technically, this is '80s hair metal.
事实上 这首是80年代的轻金属
What?
什么?
Right.
听着
I'll have you know that that track was number one
告诉你 这首歌曾经是各大排行榜榜首
in 25 separate countries in 1986. 25.
1986年 它足足称霸了25个不同的国家
Now, I think that qualifies it as an all-time rock classic. Don't you?
你还敢说它不是摇滚乐里面经典吗?
Yeah. Well, we had different childhoods, mate.
嗯 可能我们成长背景不同
While you were jumping around in your bedroom to men in tights,
可能你喜欢在你房间里面玩
I was keeping it fresh,
但是 我都不喜欢呆在房间
rolling with the brothers, you know what I'm saying, y'all?
我喜欢在外面的时候和朋友一起玩 你能理解吗?
- Dusting off my AK, motherfucker.   - Well, you missed out.
- 擦我的假AK枪 厉害吧  - 该死的 住口
You don't know what you're talking about anyway.
你究竟想要说什么
I used to lie over there, on my bed with my headphones on.
以前我习惯戴着耳机躺在这边的床上
And I'd just disappear into my imagination.
陷入音乐当中
Gran always said I had a very vivid imagination.
奶奶说我的想象力很丰富
Oh, I could be anyone.
我喜欢人物扮演
Sometimes I'd be this rock star, half man, half elf,
有时我会扮玩摇滚的明星 半人半妖那样
with this great mane of golden hair, down to my waist
带上及腰长的金色假发
and all the girls would be yelling,
想象女孩子们为我尖叫
"Oh, Tony. Let me touch it, Tony. Let me touch it. Let me touch it."
"托尼 我在这儿 我爱你 托尼"
This was your bedroom?
你睡在这里?
- Eh?   - You had a bed down here?
- 啊?  - 你居然在这里放床?
Oh, mate.
先生
Me and this launderette go way back.
我在这里长大的
You see, my mum died when I was quite young
我很小的时候 我妈就不在了
and I didn't have any other family, so I was sent to live with my gran.
我没有被亲戚领养 只能和我奶奶一起生活
At the launderette.
在这家洗衣店
She took me in, bless her heart, and looked after me,
她很善良 让我住这儿 照顾我
but she decided there wasn't enough room
可是这里太小了
for two people upstairs in the flat.
两个人住楼上就太挤了
So she made me a room down here.
所以她给我在这儿弄了一个房间
Down in the cellar.
就在地窖
It was, well...
这儿...
It took a bit of getting used to.
因为一开始我还不太习惯
But she only locked the hatch very late at night.
她都很晚才锁上地窖的门
And I was allowed out, to see the people coming and going.
平时我也可以出来 看看外面的顾客
To watch them wash.
看他们洗衣服的样子
You.
啊 原来是你
Oh, Tony, you poor thing.
天啊 托尼 你太可怜了
What do you mean? Poor thing?
你在胡说八道什么? 我怎么可怜了?
You were abandoned, Tone.
你也是被抛弃的小孩啊 托尼
Mate, I had this whole massive bedroom to myself.
同志们 这里这么大都是我的房间耶
This is a cellar, Tone. A cellar.
这里是地窖 不是你的房间 托尼
- But...   - Look, it's Dickensian.
- 胡说...  - 这里根本是狄更斯小说里面的地窖
- How big was your fucking bedroom?   - That's not the point.
- 你的房间有多好?  - 那不是重点
Jesus. What kind of woman keeps a child in a cellar?
老天爷 什么女人居然忍心让小孩住在地窖?
Hey, don't you say a word about my gran.
喂 警告你不要污蔑我奶奶
My gran was a very special person.
我奶奶是世界上最好的人
That's the kid talking.
别幼稚了
Any mother, even a twisted hag bitch of a mother is better than no mother.
就算你有一个神经病一样的妈妈 也总是比一个人强
Come on, Tone. You were dumped. Alone. In a cellar.
承认吧 你被抛弃了 托尼 被孤独地丢在地窖里面
Yeah, all right, thank you very much, Sigmund Freud.
谢谢你精彩的分析 弗洛伊德
You're the one tied up in a basement.
现在被绑在地窖的是你
I'm the one feeding the press. Baffling the police.
而我 不仅轰动了新闻界 还让警界望而生畏
I'm conducting the whole thing like an orchestra.
我像指挥管弦乐一样自导自演这些谋杀
I'm like the André Previn of serial killers.
我是连环杀手界的指挥家安德烈·普列文
Mate, I have studied serial killers and you are not it.
老兄 我很了解什么是连环杀手 你才不是连环杀手
- A serial killer is an artist.   - Hey, I'm all about elegant design.
- 连环杀手是艺术家  - 我也是艺术家
Tell them, Gran. I am an artist, aren't I?
奶奶 告诉他们 我是位艺术家
I'm like a sculptor, sculpting in crime.
我是雕刻家 我雕刻我的犯罪作品
Don't tell me you've got your bloody grandmother down here too.
我的天 你不要说这个作品是你奶奶的尸体
Well, of course I have. I'm a serial killer, aren't I?
聪明 现在还敢说我不是连环杀手吗?
It's been done, mate! Come up with something original.
够了 兄弟 够了! 恢复理智吧
I did the Hanoi Handshake!
我一手打响了河内友谊大使的名堂!
Sounds like two Vietnamese gentlemen in a public convenience!
这名字听起来像是越南人打招呼说的傻话!
He's right. It does, actually.
是啊 这个名字不好
"Can I give you a handshake? I give you handshake."
"来握个手吧? 来握个手吧"
Please! Have some bloody respect, will you?
混蛋! 你就不能放尊重一点吗?
That's it.
到时间了
- Spin's started.   - No!
- 开始甩水了  - 不!
- No!   - Don't!
- 不要!  - 不!
Shut it! Shut up! Shut up!
闭嘴! 安静! 闭嘴!
- No!   - Try making fun of this, dead man.
- 不要!  - 享受死亡的过程吧 兄弟
Say hello to my bowie knife. I call him Dave.
和我的刀打个招呼吧 它叫戴维
David the Bowie Knife? Sounds like a character from my stories.
居然叫戴维? 这名字和我小说里面的人一样
Dave doesn't like you.
戴维说它讨厌你
He's telling me to do it.
它想要赶快杀了你
I'm gonna do it.
我要听戴维的话
Tony.
托尼
You can't reason with a serial killer.
没法和一个连环杀手讲道理的
- Oh, Jack.   - Just go, go, go. Please go, go, go.
- 天啊 杰克  - 快跑 拜托你快跑
Go on, go. Go get help. Hop. Hop! Hop.
快跑 快快快 找人来帮忙 跳上去! 快点
Hop. Hop. Hop.
快跳 快跳
Run!
跑!
Sorry. I am sorry.
对不起 不好意思我不能放过你
- No, Tony.   - No, I can't let you go.
- 不要 托尼  - 对不起 我不能让你走
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry. This is how it has to end.
对不起 我是真心的 可是我必须杀了你
- Tony, please, leave her alone.   - Sorry, mate, she saw me with you.
- 托尼 拜托你 放过她吧  - 对不起 但是她知道我会杀了你
- No turning back now.   - Jack. Jack.
- 别转过身来  - 杰克 杰克
- Do something. Please.   - What? What?
- 救我 拜托你救救我  - 我要怎么做?
You're a writer, aren't you? Tell him a fucking story.
你不是小说家吗? 快编个故事
- A story?   - Right, this is it.
- 故事?  - 够了 我已经等得不耐烦了
No, wait. No, she's right. Let me tell you a story.
不 等等 她说的对 让我讲个故事吧
- A story?   - Yes, please.
- 讲故事?  - 对 拜托你
It's a dead man's last wish.
这个是一个将死之人的最后请求
It's a story to end the cycle.
让这个故事作为我生命的句点
- How long's it going to take?   - Not long.
- 故事会很长吗?  - 不长
- Because I haven't got long.   - Neither have I.
- 我等不了太久  - 我也没有什么时间耗了
Oh, all right, dead man.
好吧 既然你快死了 讲吧
But make it good because it's the last thing you're gonna write.
不过警告你讲个精彩一点的 你以后也没有机会讲了
- Yeah, yeah.   - No pressure, though.
- 是的 我了解  - 不过也不要给自己太大压力
Okay. I have to start right at the beginning.
好的 故事是这样发生的
Once upon a time,
很久很久以前
there was a hedgehog whose name...
有一个刺猬 它的名字叫做...
A hedgehog?
刺猬?
Yes. Yes. Whose name...
对 它叫...
You're about to die and you want to tell a story about a hedgehog?
你都快没命了 你的故事居然讲一只刺猬?
Mate, please, just bear with me.
老大 您先听我讲
Okay, you sitting comfortably?
好了 你现在能舒服地听故事吗?
Once upon a time...
很久很久以前...
not so long ago...
其实也不是很久之前...
there was a hedgehog...
有一只刺猬
whose name...
它叫做
was Brian.
布莱恩
Brian lived in a cave deep in the forest,
布莱恩住在森林的最深处的洞穴里
a dark and terrible place called the Wyrd Wild Wood.
那里又黑又可怕 被称为狂野之林
After dark, the forest would echo with howls and screams.
入夜后 森林里充满猫头鹰可怕的叫声
And sometimes it seemed to Brian as if even the moon
有时布莱恩看着月亮
conspired against him.
都觉得阴谋横生
But the more afraid Brian became, the angrier he got,
虽然布莱恩的内心一边害怕 也一边累积愤怒
until one night, frightened out of his wits...
有一天晚上 怒气冲破了他的理智
he turned himself into a terrifying monster.
他决定化身为猛兽
He put on weight, painted his face
他变得高大强壮 还在脸上涂上迷彩
and started insisting on being addressed as Balthazar the Berserker.
开始将自己打扮的跟战士一样
But then a strange thing happened.
可是意外的事情发生了
Brian received an unexpected visitor.
来了一位不速之客
"Come any closer and I'll scratch your eyes out."
"再靠近我就戳瞎你的眼睛"
He snarled angrily at the ?ickering eyes in the trees.
他生气地对着来客咆哮
"Brian?" Whispered a voice.
"布莱恩?" 一个温柔的声音轻叫着
"Is that really you?"
"真的是你吗?"
"Who the fuck are you calling Brian?" said Brian,
"你是谁啊管我叫布莱恩? "
as menacingly as he could manage. "Why, Brian, it is you."
他凶巴巴的问道 "可是 你是布莱恩啊"
It was Harold, his brother, last seen by the road,
原来是哈罗德 他好久不见的兄弟
walking with mother a long time ago.
上次见到他和妈妈一起离开 已经是很久之前的事了
He said, "I'm so happy I found you, Brian, old chap."
"好开心终于见到你了 我的老伙计 布莱恩"
"I've been terribly lonely and fancied a chat."
"我一个人太孤单了 想找你谈谈"
But Brian had crossed that road and never looked back.
可布莱恩已经不是以前的他了
He'd erased the memory and his soul was now black.
他忘掉所有的回忆 他成了一个可怕的人
"Harold, mate. I hate to be blunt."
"哈罗德 兄弟 我也不想这么直接的"
"But look in the mirror, you prickly idiot."
"照照镜子吧 你就像带刺的傻瓜"
"You're a worthless, pathetic, sniveling fool."
"你就是一个无用 可怜 爱哭的白痴"
"I'd rather spend time with the worms in my stool."
"我宁愿坐长虫的凳子也不想理你"
With that he chased him into the trees and over the dells, screaming,
当哈罗德坚持追着他 跟出树林 布莱恩大叫
"I'll eat you for supper or meet you in hell."
"我会把你当晚餐吃了或者亲自杀了你"
But fate intervened and Brian got lost.
命运开了个玩笑 布莱恩迷路了
And to make matters worse, there was a treacherous fog.
更糟糕的是 到处都是大雾弥漫
"Hello, " he cried. "Is anyone there?"
"喂" 布莱恩大叫 "有人吗?"
But no one replied, and Brian got scared.
一直没人回应 布莱恩开始怕了
And that's when he saw he wasn't alone.
可是 他发现 原来还有别人
A small, crumpled body was lying in the road.
有一个小小的 蜷缩的尸体 就在路边
"Why didn't you leave me?" said Brian.
"你为什么不丢下我?" 布莱恩问道
"And just let me die?"
"为什么不让我死?"
"You're my brother," said Harold. "How on earth could I?"
"你是我的兄弟" 哈罗德回答 "我永远不会那样做的"
And that's when they heard the pitiful cries
他们突然听到了一阵可怜的哭声
of a very small hedgehog whose mother just died.
是一个刚失去妈妈的刺猬宝宝
And suddenly Brian just started to blub.
布莱恩突然大哭了
He picked up the babe and gave it a hug.
他抱起婴儿
"This little thing, you know, reminds me of us.
“这个小家伙让我想起我们”
"Left all alone when Mum caught that bus."
“像妈妈被车撞死后 被丢下的我们”
"The spell has been broken," said Harold.
“已经过去了” 哈罗德说
"It's time to break free. You're not really a monster.
“走出这段阴霾吧 你不是坏物”
"You're a hedgehog, like me."
"你和我一样 都是刺猬"
I tell you what, that is a beautiful story.
你知道吗 这是个很好的故事
- I suppose they...   - Adopted the baby hedgehog. Yes.
- 最后他们...  - 领养了那只刺猬宝宝
Oh, mate.
天啊 兄弟
It's symbolic. You see, they discovered their true selves.
这是一个象征 他们最终发现了真实的自我
They start again where they left off
他们忘掉失母之痛
before the trauma of losing their mum.
开始了新的生活
I tell you, that was my life, right there in that cave.
你知道吗 这和我一样 我现在也住在那个洞穴里面
I'm not a monster, am I?
可是我不是怪物 对吗?
No. You just need some help.
你不是 你只是需要帮助
I'll let you into a secret. I'm not even a proper serial killer.
告诉你一个秘密吧 我不是严格意义上的连环杀手
That Vietnamese bloke, the one in the marshes, I didn't kill him.
死在沼泽地的那个越南人 和我没有关系
- What?   - No, he must've tripped and fell.
- 什么?  - 他只是自己摔跤 掉下去了
He was dead when I found him.
我找到他的时候 他已经死了
Yeah, but the fingers, the Hanoi Handshake?
那 那些河内友谊大使砍下来的手指呢?
Oh, yeah, yeah. I did do that.
那些是我砍的
Well, otherwise, he was just a bloke in a ditch.
反正他已经摔死在那条沟里了
Oh, her? It's just a mannequin.
哦 那个女的吗? 是假人来的
I found her in a bin outside Topshop.
我在的特普店垃圾桶找到的
So you're not a killer, then.
那你根本称不上是杀手咯
You're like me.
你和我一样
We were both abandoned.
我们都被抛弃了
We're the same.
我们是一样的
We're like...
我们就像是...
Yes. Brothers.
兄弟
Er, it's... It's not mine. I just... I picked it up.
呃 这个... 不是我的... 我捡回来的
Brother?
好兄弟?
- Help.  - Help.
- 救命  - 救命
"So Harold and his long-lost brother Brian"
"于是哈罗德 和他失散多年的兄弟布莱恩"
"lived happily afterwards in the old hedgerow beside the churchyard."
"在教堂后面的老树篱里 开心地生活在一起"
And remember, no matter how dark and scary those woods may seem,
记住 不管你身处在多么黑暗可怕的树林
there's a way across the road for a hedgehog brave enough to cross it.
你一定可以像刺猬一样 勇敢地走出那里
Thank you.
谢谢
- Hey.   - Hey, hi.
- 你好  - 你好
- You look fantastic.   - Thank you.
- 你真漂亮  - 谢谢
That was a wonderful story.
这个故事真的太棒了
Congratulations. Perfect synthesis of Jungian and Freudian thought.
恭喜你 这个故事完美综合了荣格和弗洛伊德的思想
Harold's lost self is recovered,
哈罗德重新找到迷失的自我
whilst acknowledging the important role that the false self
承认自身的不足之处 是很重要的
played in surviving the terror of abandonment.
忍受被抛弃的痛苦
Well, it's all credit to you, Professor Friedkin.
这要多谢你 弗里德金教授
Next book, Harold must address his destructive Oedipal complex
在下一本书 哈罗德要处理好个人的恋母情结
and help Brian with his tendency towards malignant anal hoarding.
然后帮助布莱恩走出他潜在的阴暗面
Darling, I've brought someone I think you should finally meet.
亲爱的 我给你带来了一个重要的客人
Harvey Humphries.
哈维·汉弗莱斯
You. You never came to see me, did you?
你 就是你 一直没来见我?
Oh, you are a very, very naughty boy.
你真是太不听话了
Harvey's still very interested in "Decades of Death", Jack.
哈维到现在还是对那本"死亡年代"很感兴趣 杰克
maybe you two can get together and discuss it later?
不然有机会你们一起讨论一下?
Can you see the spider?
你看见那只蜘蛛了吗?
and the farmer in his field?
还有他地里的农民?
can you see the lovely ladybird?
看得见那只可爱的瓢虫吗?
and what about the little frightened hedgehog?
还看得见受惊了的那只刺猬吗?
Jack?
杰克?
Jack.
杰克
Are you all right?
你还好吗
Er, yes, sorry.
我没事
Hey, what about that dinner you promised me?
我们什么时候去吃之前约好的晚饭啊?
Erm, I'll get back to you, okay, on the whole thing.
等这里结束 我会找你的
- I'll think about it. I will.   - Call me.
- 我会认真考虑  - 记得找我
Absolutely.
一定会
- Congratulations.   - Thank you.
- 恭喜你  - 谢谢
- Congratulations.   - Thank you, thank you.
- 恭喜  - 谢谢 谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢
Once upon a time, there was a hedgehog called Harold,
很久很久以前 有一只叫哈罗德的刺猬
who one day set out on a journey.
有一天他想去旅行
When he reached the far side of the wood,
他离开森林 越走越远
he came to a large flowing river, dancing with speckled light.
他见到一条宽阔的河 河面泛着星星点点的光芒
Without a moment's hesitation, Harold threw himself into the water.
他毫不犹豫 跳进了河里
The current carried him far away
河浪将他带去远方
and he was never seen again.
他再也没有回来过
Morning. Morning, you two. Morning, madam.
早上好 早上好 女士们早上好
Bye, then.
再见
What a fucking...
搞什么...
- Twat.   - Cock.
- 白痴  - 混蛋
Fucking dickhead. Wanker.
该死的混蛋 讨厌鬼
-==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：景鲤
翻译：景鲤 欣欣然 Mabb 苑琳琳
校对：veray Uriana
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org